Elyza Bleau

310-890-2381 | elyzableau.om@gmail.com | Brooklyn, NY https://www.linkedin.com/in/elyzableau | https://github.com/bleauwonder https://elyzableau.dev/

Career Summary

Passionate Full Stack Web Developer with experience at the intersection of Coding, Art and Communication. Significant project experience building applications augmented by artistic and design skills gained through years of visual and performing arts. Effective communication skills as evidenced by over ten years of administrative leadership, teaching experience, and writing expertise from a wide range of industries. An innovative and creative spirit with a love of coding detective work.

Education

Columbia University New York, NY | Full Stack Web Development Certificate (2019)
University of California San Diego La Jolla, CA | Master of Education Elementary and Music Mount St. Joseph University Cincinnati, OH | Bachelor of Arts Music (French Horn)

Applications Built

musability | Full-Stack Mobile Application

https://github.com/bleauwonder/musability

A mobile application for people with physical disabilities and their friends to find and review local music venues

- Reworking for production in 2020, please see GitHub ReadMe for gifs of the prototype
- React Native, React Native libraries, node, yarn, JavaScript (ES6), HTML

Art Deco Memory Game | Front-End React Application

https://cryptic-everglades-73436.herokuapp.com/

Memory game to remember which pictures you chose

- Class homework enhanced by extra CSS
- React, Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript (ES6)

I Love Sitcoms | Front-End Application with 2 APIs

https://bleauwonder.github.io/Giphy-Time/

A just-for-fun application to gather information and gifs on sitcoms and add your own

- Class homework enhanced by the idea of adding a second API that adds information on each sitcom in a dynamic environment
- Used HTML, Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery, Giphy API, OMDB API

Technical Skills

JavaScript (ES6), HTML5, CSS3, Sass, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, MySQL, Handlebars, React.js, Node.js, Heroku, Git, Terminal Command (bash), Computer Science Fundamentals, Responsive Design, WordPress, Microsoft Exchange, O365, Mac, PC, Google Suite, Cloud-Based Solutions, Canvas, ADP, Adobe DC: advanced Photoshop/Lightroom

Professional Skills

Project Coordination, Office Management, Vendor Management, Customer Service, Public Speaking/Presentations, Training, Teaching, Lesson Plans, Scheduling, Problem Solving, Recruiting, Employee Relations, Writing Articles/Blogs, Agile and SCRUM methodology

Professional Experience

iCIMS | Software Engineer | New York, NY

08/2020-Present

Work on the front-end CRM Angular team to create a unique CRM

• Create typescript files and modules in Angular 9 and 10 for the client-side portion (CRM) of the iCIMS SaaS

iCIMS | Junior Web Developer | New York, NY

12/2019-Present

Work on the front-end Branding and JavaScript teams to create best UI for clients

- Adjust CSS to customize Angular Material Design for each client's branding parameters
- Adjust for media queries and discrepancies in differing browsers using CSS, LESS and SCSS
- Help create templates for a new price-point for customers using HTML, CSS, JavaScript in Angular

YAI Network | Data Analyst | New York, NY

08/2019 - 02/2020

Analyzed employee and business process data in Workday, as well as work with IT in SQL.

- Helped new employees move through the hiring process in Workday through troubleshooting where the process stopped and adjusting it.
- Ran reports for the HR and Payroll departments, and analyze what data is incorrect to correct it in the system.

YAI Network | Human Resources Generalist | New York, NY

09/2018 - 08/2019

Recruited and provided Employee Relations for 5 clinics and all residential nursing, specifically bringing in LPNs, RNs, MDs, OTs, PTs, and LMSWs.

- Successfully created requisitions by writing accurate and correct job descriptions and posting them in ADP and job boards while screening candidates for initial contact with hiring manager
- Effectively researched and implemented best office practices to help streamline processes with SharePoint and spreadsheets to solve hiring issues
- Supported employees to work through problems with each other in a proactive way
- Ad hoc help with central office recruiting (finding a Web Development star, a CRM guru, and a database Manager

YAI Network | Project Coordinator | New York, NY

02/2018-09/2018

Used knowledge of information technologies improvement methodologies, including, but not limited to large Non-Profit agencies, Telecomm, Healthcare, Cloud Services (Azure), and Apple support while leading IT team in Agile huddles.

- Effectively created spreadsheets, presentations and other deliverables using Microsoft Office 365 as necessary for client engagement. Identified potential engagement sources and potential add-on opportunities
- Successfully developed content and taught Office 365 in a training environment with a small team, in preparation for an organization-wide migration
- Coordinated best development practices to reach the company-wide fundraising goal, as well as participated as a key team member in filming and introducing Virtual Reality videos to the greater YAI community

Freelance | Photographer | New York, NY

02/2015-Present

Take photographs for events and headshots

- Utilize Photoshop and Lightroom to adjust photos to look inviting on the web and in print
- Help clients build their brand through the stories they tell in their photographs

Freelance | WordPress Developer/Branding Specialist | Los Angeles, CA/NY, NY

05/2007-03/2016

Created websites on Wordpress.org and taught other entrepreneurs how to use it over Wix and Square Space

- Utilized HTML to adjust templates to make them as custom as possible
- Helped other entrepreneurs find their voice in their brand, website, and photos

Volunteer Activities/Additional Skills

- Professional musician, and public speaker/storyteller
- Full-Stack Web Development for entrepreneurial friends
- Staff at an urban farm in Queens and member of Hudson River Community Sailing
- Teacher volunteer at the Santa Monica Pier Aquarium
- 500-hour certified yoga instructor, music instructor, tutor, health coach